### ALEXIS PORTOCARRERO

Lima, Peru – alexis.portocarrero@usil.pe – +51 967527084 – WhatsApp – LinkedIn

### **EXECUTIVE SUMMARY**

University student in Software Engineering with one year of experience in application and video game development. Fluent in Spanish and English, Java, Python, C#, Unity and GitHub. Knowledge of coding loops, script logic, UI, and retaining player or application data offline or online.

#### **SKILLS**

Application developer - Game designer and tester - Game Programmer - Quality Assurance - Decipher Faults

### COMPETENCE

- Programming languages: C#, Java, Python.
- Software: Unity, Github, blender.
- E-Learning Developing: Power Point, canvas

### **EDUCATION**

## UNIVERSIDAD SAN IGNACIO DEL LOYOLA(USIL)

Lima, Peru

### **Software Engineering**

In progress (70%)

Relevant courses: English 6, Fundamentals of Calculus, Introduction to Computer Science, advanced POO, mobile apps, databases, html and PHP..

### **AUSTRAL UNIVERSITY**

Argentina, Buenos Aires

#### **Biomedical Engineering**

Up to 4th cycle 2021

Relevant courses: Bioinformatics, Statistics, Algorithms and data structures, Advanced programming, Organic and biological chemistry, Introduction to engineering.

**Innova Schools** 

Lima, Perú

### Secondary upper fifth

2018

Relevant courses: Mathematics, Probability, Physics, Electricity, Computer Science and a wide variety of web courses in English, language and mathematics. Average 18 out of 20

#### **EXPERIENCE**

### **BitVR**

# Remote(Lima, Buenos Aires)

### **Intern Game Developer**

Dec 2021 - Present

- I programmed in unity apps for data collection, variable specific calculations, and fast interaction applications.
- I programmed in unity 2D and 3D video games in RogueLike, Indie, Tower Defense, Clicker, FPS and Tap genres.
- Analyzed failures of past programs for updates and continued development.
- I safeguarded the quality standards of the programs and their correct functioning.
- I programmed in VR by using unity focusing on the user experience.

# **Game Developer Freelance**

Freelance Dec 2021 - Present

- Developer of games and applications with different themes and technologies correctly adapted to the client's needs.
- Programmer of different aspects of videogames such as sounds, graphics, scripts, interfaces, etc.
- Developer of gameplay and mechanics for different types of projects for different clients.
- Improvement in SOLID pattern.

### ALEXIS PORTOCARRERO

Lima, Peru – alexis.portocarrero@usil.pe – +51 967527084 – WhatsApp – LinkedIn

#### **RESUMEN EJECUTIVO**

Estudiante Universitario en Ingeniería de Software con un año de experiencia en desarrollo de aplicaciones y videojuegos. Dominio de español e inglés, Java, Python, C#, Unity y GitHub. Conocimiento en codificar loops, lógica de scripts, UI y retener datos del jugador o de aplicación de forma offline o online.

### **HABILIDADES CLAVE**

Desarrollador de aplicaciones - Diseñador y testeador de Juegos - Programador de Juegos - Asegurador de Calidad - Descifrar Fallos

### **COMPETENCIAS**

- Lenguajes de programación: C#, Java, Python.
- Software: Unity, Github, blender.
- Desarrollo e-Learning: Power Point, canvas

## **EDUCACIÓN**

### UNIVERSIDAD SAN IGNACIO DEL LOYOLA(USIL)

Lima, Perú

#### Ingeniería De Software

En curso(70%)

Cursos relevantes: Inglés 6, Fundamentos del cálculo, Introducción a la ciencia computacional, POO avanzada, aplicaciones móviles, base de datos, HTML y PHP.

### **UNIVERSIDAD AUSTRAL**

Argentina, Buenos Aires

### Ingeniería Biomédica

Hasta 4to ciclo 2021

Cursos relevantes: Bioinformática, Estadística, Algoritmos y estructura de datos, Programación Avanzada, Quimica organica y biologica, introduccion a la ingenieria.

### Colegio Innova Schools

Lima, Perú

#### Secundaria quinto superior

2018

Cursos relevantes: Matemáticas, Probabilidad, Física, Electricidad, Computación y alta variedad de cursos web de inglés, lenguaje y matemática. Promedio 18 sobre 20

### **EXPERIENCIA LABORAL**

**BitVR** 

Remoto(Lima, Buenos aires)

Intern Game Developer

Dec 2021 - Actualidad

- Programé en unity apps de recolección de datos, cálculos de variables específicas y aplicaciones de interacción apresurada.
- Programé en unity videojuegos en 2D y 3D de genero RogueLike, Indie, Tower Defense, Clicker, FPS y Tap.
- Analice fallas de programas pasados para sus actualizaciones y continuo desarrollo.
- Salvaguardé los estándares de calidad de los programas y su correcto funcionamiento.
- Programé en VR priorizando la experiencia del cliente y la correcta funcionalidad.

# **Game Developer Freelance**

Freelance Dec 2021 - Actualidad

- Desarrollador de juegos y aplicaciones con diferentes temas y tecnologías correctamente adaptadas para las necesidades del cliente.
- Programador de diferentes aspectos de videojuegos como sonidos, gráficos, scripts, interfaces, etc.
- Desarrollador de la jugabilidad y mecánicas para diferentes tipos de proyectos para diferentes clientes.
- Mejora en el patrón SOLID.